Guide to the History of Medicine Picture File, 1523-2002 and undated RL.00570
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- History of Medicine Picture File: People Series, approx. 1851 items
  - Ether Day: "Old-time Boston doctors on 'Ether Day'," from Boston Globe, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    Photograph of approximately 40 prominent physicians, many of them active in Massachusetts, gathered in 1896 for 50th anniversary of use of ether in surgery. Includes Silas Weir Mitchell, Charles P. Curtis, Henry Bowditch, Abraham Jacobi, Sidney Otis, Lord and Lady Playfair, Isaac Galloupe, Benjamin Cotting, William J. Morton, F.C. Shattuck, William H. Welch, and others. Newspaper cutting mounted on board.
    Comes with pamphlet, Hinckley's Who Was Who on Ether Day, from an exhibit at Boston Library, 1962, describing the protagonists in Hinckley's famous painting of the first public demonstration of ether as an anesthetic.
  - Ettmüler, Michael, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Ettmüller, Michael Ernestus (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Eustachi, Bartolomeo, 1520-1574 [Eustachius] (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Eve, Paul F. (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Evelyn, John, 1620-1760, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Also contains picture of Mayow, John.
  - Everard, Giles (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Everard, John (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Ewing, Harvey Milligan (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Fabernaemontenus, Jacobus Theodurus, 1524-1590 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Fabricius von Hilden, Wilhelm (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Fabrizzi, Girolamo, 1537-1619 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Fagon, Guy Crescent (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Fallopius, Gabriel, 1523-1562 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Faraday, Michael (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Fergusson, Sir William (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Fergusson, Sir William, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Fernel, Jean (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Ferrier, John, box size: 16.5 x 20.5 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ferriar, John, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Ferris, H. B. (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - "Fifth Conference on Shock and Circulatory Homeostasis, Princeton, NJ, 1955 Dec. 1-2," photo portrait of attendees, 1955, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Figuierdo, J. J. (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Finney, John M. (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Finsen, Niels R. (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Fioravanti, Leonardo (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fisch, Max H. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fishbein, Morris (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Flechsig, Paul Emil, 1847-1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Flint, Austin (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Florey, Howard (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Flourens, Marie Jean Pierre, 1794-1867 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Foerster, Richard (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Follin, Hermann, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Consists of a small engraving of Follin, in a large mat, from frontispiece of a volume published in Antwerp, 1618: Amuletum Antonianum, seu luis pestiferæ fuga...cui accessit utilis libellus de cauteriis.
  - Förster, Richard (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fonteyn, Johannes, 1574-1628 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Foot, Jesse (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Foster, Michael, 1836-1907 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fothergill, John Dr., 1712-1780 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Fox, J. M. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fracastorius, Hieronymius (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Frank, J. P. (John Peter), 1745-1821 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Frank, Robert T. (b. 1875) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Franklin, Benjamin (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Franklin, Benjamin, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Color reproduction of painting by Benjamin West of Franklin with kite.
  - Frazier, Charles H. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Freher, Paul, d. 1473 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Friend, John (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Freind, John, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Fuchs, Leonhart [also Leonhard], 1501-1566 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fulton, John, 4 black-and-white glossy photographs (Box 4, Folder 24)
    At Vesalius book publication party; also shown with Madeline Stanton, Mrs. Harvey Cushing, and Arturo Castiglioni.
  - Fulton, John (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Inscribed to Henry and Ida Schuman.
  - Futcher, Thomas Barnes (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Galenus (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Gall, Franz Joseph (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Garrison, Fielding (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Garth, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Garth, Samuel, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Includes slides.
  - Gegenbaur, Carl (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Gerhardt, Karl (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Geschickter, Charles F. (b. 1901) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Gilbert, David (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Gilbert, Nicoles, Joseph Laurent, 1715-1750 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Gillingham, Francis John (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Gilson, Helen (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Glisson, Francis, 1597-1677 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Goldzieher, Maximillian A. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Golgi, Camillo (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Gooch, Robert, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "Dr. Goodman, 1929" (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Gowers, William R. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Graaf, Regner De, 1641-1673 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Graefe, Albrecht von (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Gratarolus, Guilelmus (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Gray, Henry, 1825-1861 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Greenhill, J. P. (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Gregory, James (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Gregory, John (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Greulich, William Walter (b. 1899) (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Grew, Nehemiah, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Grissom, Eugene, M. D. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Grollman, Arthur (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Gross, Samuel David (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Gross, Samuel David, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Scene from surgical theater, Jefferson Medical College, color reproduction of painting, "The Gross Clinic, 1875."
  - Guenther, Johann (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Guillotin, Joseph I. (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Guld, Fielding (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Gunn, John C. (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Guy de Chauliac (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Gybels, Jau (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Haak, Theodore (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Hahneman, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Hales, Stephen (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Halford, Sir Henry (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Hall, John, 1529?-1566? (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Hall, Marshall (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Haller, Albrecht von, 1708-1777 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Haller, Albertus [Baron Albrecht von Haller], box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hamilton, Alexander, 1739-1802, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Small engraving on cardstock, 1786. Accompanying note says the subject is Alexander Hamilton (1739-1802), Professor of Midwifery at Edinburgh University. Image shows him walking, in profile, with two women.
  - Hammond, Roland (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Hammond, William Alexander (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Hanes, Frederic Moir (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Hanson, Michael Frederick (Duke physician) (Box 7, Folder 48)
    Signed snapshot photograph of Hanson together with colleague Keith Oliver (Duke '44). Filed under "Oliver."
  - Harrison, J. Hartwell (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Hartman, Carl Gottfried (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Harvey, Gideon (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Harvey, William, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 6)
    One engraving, two copies.
  - Harvey, William, box size: 16x20 inches; 5 items (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Five items; one is a woodcut by Horace Gerrard, 1923. One image features Harvey in dissection theater. Includes slides.
  - Harvey, William, "Harvey demonstrating the circulation of the blood to Charles the First," black-and-white matted reproduction of 1842 engraving by Robert Hannah, 20th century, distributed by CIBA Pharmaceuticals, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Harvey, William, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Haygarth, John (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Hays, Isaac, 1796-1879 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Head, Henry, 1861-1940 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Heberden, William (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Heberden, William, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Two copies. Includes slide.
  - Hebra, Ferdinand von, 1818-1880 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Hegar, Alfred, 1830-1914 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Heister, Lorenz (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Helmholtz, Hermann Ludwig Ferdinand von, 1821-1894 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Helmont, Jan Baptist van (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Henle, Friedrich Gustav Jacob (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Henschen, Folke (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hensen, Viktor (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Herrick, C. Judson (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Heubner, Otto (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Heurnius, Otho, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Heurnius, Otho, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Hicks, John Braxton (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Highmore, Nathaniel (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hill, Archibald (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hill, John (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hippocrates (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hippocrates, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - His, Wilhelm, Jr., box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - His, Wilhelm, Sr. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hitchings, Dr. George H. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Hitzig, Eduard, 1838-1907 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hobbes, Thomas (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Hodge, Hugh (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Hoesslin, Rudolf von (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Hofbauer, J. Isfred Isidor (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Hoff, Jacobus Henricus Van 'T, 1852-1911 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Hoffa, Albert (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Holland, Philemon (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, box size: 11x14 inches (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Early portrait, circa 1850, from daguerreotype attributed to Southworth and Hawes.
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Later portrait.
  - Holt, Luther Emmett, box size: 16.5 x 20.5 inches (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Hooker, Sir Joseph, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Hooper, William (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hope, James (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Hopkins, Sir Frederick Gowland, 1861-1947 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Johns Hopkins Medical School Pathology Department photos, 1921-circa 1930 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Black-and-white photos, chiefly of groups of Pathology staff. One photo circa 1930 depicts doctors gathered in medical lab, and reads: "Tuesday morning conference in the old autopsy room...the material used at these conferences during 1930 was brought to Duke and formed the basis of the origin of Duke collection [used?] for the first class in Pathology in 1931."
  - Johns Hopkins Hospital and Medical School, surgical staff, circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Black-and-white photographs of eleven members of the surgical staff, including Cushing, Halsted and Bloodgood.
  - Hoppins, Johannes (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Hordlicka, Aleo (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Horine, Emmet F., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Horine is shown in black-and-white photo with three other men, one of whom is most likely Henry Schumman, rare book dealer, to whom the image is inscribed, June 1948. They are examining the publication Pioneer Life in Kentucky, written by Daniel Drake and published by Schumann in 1948.
  - Hosack, David (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Hoskins, Roy Graham (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Howard, John (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Howe, Samuel Gridley (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Howell, William H. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Howland, John, 1873-1926 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Hüfner, Gustav von (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Huhner, Max (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Humboldt, Alexander von (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Hunter, John, 1728-1793 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Hunter, John, 1728-1793, box size: 16.5 x 20.5 inches; 3 items (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Hunter, John, 1728-1793, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Hunter, John, 1728-1793, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
    1814 engraving from painting by Sir Joshua Reynolds.
  - Hunter, William (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Hunter, William, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Huntington, George I., 1861-1927 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Hurd, Henry M. (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Huxham, John, box size: 16.5 x 20.5 inches (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Huxley, Thomas Henry (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Hyde, William (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Indagine, Joannes (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Ivy, Andrew Conway (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Jackson, Charles T. (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Jackson, James (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Jackson, Samuel (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Jacobi, Mary Putnam (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - James, Robert (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - James, Thomas C. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Janos, Bokay (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Jauregg, Julius R. Wagner (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Jenner, Edward, 1749-1823 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Jenner, Edward, 1749-1823, box size: 16x20 inches; 2 items (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Includes photo of sculpture with French caption, Jenner vaccinating his own young son.
  - Jenner, Edward, "Premiere inoculation du Vaccin (14 Mai 1796)," black-and-white print by Gaston Melingue, 1879, published as photogravure by Goupil, 1880, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Jennerian Society, certificate of honorary membership issued to the Hon. Lord King (probably Peter King, seventh Lord King, 1776-1833, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Signed by John Fox, Secretary of the Jennerian Society. Engraving shows a large arch through which there is a view of London. In front of the arch is a figure of Jenner on a pedestal, with a scroll with names of patrons, presidents, and honorary members of the Society.
  - Johnson, Alex B. (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Johnson, Herman W. (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Johnston, George Ben, 1853-1916 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Jolly, Friedrich (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Kane, Elisha Kent (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Karsner, Howard T., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Karholr, Howard T., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Keen, William Williams (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Kelly, Howard Atwood (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Kendall, Edward Calvin (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Key, Axel (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Keys, Thomas E. (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Kitchner, William (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Klebs, Arnold C. (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Klebs, Edwin (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Kleef, Hermanus van, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Knox, Robert, 1791-1862 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Koch, Herman Carl (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Koch, Robert (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Kocher, Emil (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Koester, Karl (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Koff, Arthur Karl (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Korenshevsky, Vladimir (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Krieger, Josef (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Krogh, August, 1874-1949 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Krumbhaar, Edward Bell, 1882- (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Kulm, Joannes A. (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Kühne, Wilhelm (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Külz, Eduard (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Kunkel, Adam Joseph (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Kurzok, Raphael, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Lacaze, Louis (Box 5, Folder 84)
    On the back of this clipping of a portrait of Lacaze is an engraving entitled "Les petites causes produisent souvent de grands effets," showing a woman with two faces in the middle of a scene from the French Revolution, giving birth to a baby, who is received from under her skirts by an officer. A fragment of an article title under the image reads "accouchement de la révolution."
  - Lamarck, Jean Baptiste (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lanfranc, Archbishop, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Lansteiner, Karl (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Larrey, Dominique Jean (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Larsell, Olof (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Latham, John (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - La Valette St. George, Adolf (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lavater, John Caspar, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Lavoisier, Antoine-Laurent (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Leadbetter, Wyland F., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Leake (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Le Cat, Claude N. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Le Dran, Henri F. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Leeuwenhoek, Antonius van (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Leichtenstern, Otto (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lettsom, John Coakley (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Leube, Wilhelm (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Levret, Andre (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Lewis, Dean DeWitt (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lewis, Dio (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, Robert Morton (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Lewis, Thomas, 1881-1945 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Leyden, Ernst von (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Leydig, Franz von (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Liebermeister, Karl von (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Liebig, Justus (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Liebreich, Oscar (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Linacre, Thomas, 1460-1524 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Link, Karl Paul (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Linnaeus, Carl, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Linnaeus, Carolus (Carl Linnaeus), box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Linne, Carl (Carl Linnaeus) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Lister, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Lister, Mathew (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Litzenberg, Jennings Crawford (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Lochhead, Douglas Grant, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Locke, John, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Loeb, Jacques, 1859-1924 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Long, Crawford W. (Box 6, Folder 33.1)
  - Long, Crawford W. (with George Minot and two unidentified men): "Films of men for whom Duke [Hospital] wards were named," black-and-white negatives, undated, 4 negatives (Box 6, Folder 33.2)
  - Long, Cyril Norman Hugh (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Long, John Wesley (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Lonitzer, Adam (Lonicer, Adam, or Lonicerus, Adamus), 1528-1586 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Lorenz, Adolph (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Louis, Antoine (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Louis, Pierre Charles A. (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Lower, Richard, 1631-1691 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Lu, Leon Leslie (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Lubarsch, Otto (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Lucae, August (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Ludwig, Carl Friedrich Wilhelm, 1816-1895 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Lücke, Albert (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Lutzeyer, W., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lyall, Robert (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Maass, Clara L. (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - MacDonough, Thomas, U.S.N. (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - MacKenzie, James, 1853-1925 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - McClellan, George (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - McCrae, Thomas, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - McDowell, Ephraim (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - MacNider, W. de B. (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Magendie, François, 1783-1855 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Major, Ralph S. (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Malpighi, Marcello, 1628-1694 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Mantias, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Manson, Patrick, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mareschal, Georges (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Marey, Etienne Jules, 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Matas, Rudolph (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Matthiolus, Petrus Andreas [Mattioli, Pietro Andrea] (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Mattioli, Pietro Andrea, 1500-1577, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Maty, Matthew (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Mauriceau, François (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Mayerne, Theodore Turguet de, 1573-1655 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Mayfield, Frank, 1966, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mayo, Charles Horace (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Mayo, William James, 1861-1939 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Mayow, John, 1643-1679 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Mead, Dr. Richard, 1673-1754 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Mead, Richard, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Mease, James (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Medical Society of London, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Engraving, portrait of members from 1801(?). Includes E. Jenner, T. Bradley, J. Sims, Ware, R. Hooper, J. Lettsom, B. W. Babinton, J. Shadwell, and others. Includes slide.
  - Meissner, Georg (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Mendel, Gregor Johann, 1822-1884 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Mercer, Hugh (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Mercurialis, Hieronymus (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Mering, Josef von (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Merrett, Christopher (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Metchnikoff, Elie, 1845-1916, 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Meyer, Ludwig (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Mikulicz-Radecki, Johann von, 1850-1905 [Jan Mikulicz-Racecki] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Joseph Lyon (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miller, Genevieve (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miller, William Snow (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mills, Charles Karsner (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell, John Kearsley (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1829-1914 (multiple items) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1829-1914, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1829-1914, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Mitchill, Samuel Latham (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mixter, Samuel J. 1855-1926 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Moehlig, Robert C. [Conrad], box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Moes, Robert (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Monakow, Constantin von (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Monro, Alexander, 1697-1767, 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Montaigne, Michel de (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Moore, John (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Moreau, Renatus (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Morgagni, Giovanni Battista, 1682-1771 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Morgan, John (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Morgan, John, 1735-1789 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1866-1945 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Photograph by Tupper.
  - Morris, Caspar (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Morse, Samuel F. B. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Morton, L. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Morton, Richard (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Morton, Samuel George (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Mosso, Angelo, 1846-1910 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Mott (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Mott, Frederick Walker, box size: 16x20 inches; 2 items (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mott, Valentine (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Mueller, Johannes (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Müller, Johannes, box size: 16x20 inches; 2 items (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Muller, Johannes, 1801-1858 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Murphy, Francis, 1940s?, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Murphy, John B. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Musser, John Herr (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Mussey, Robert D. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Neander, Johannes, b. 1596 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Newton, Sir Isaac, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Newton, James (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Nightingale, Florence, 2 folders, 14 items (Box 7, Folder 35, 36)
    Includes postcards, reproductions of portraits, and other items, black-and-white and color.
    See also the Howard Kelly Collection of Florence Nightingale Prints and Photographs in the Rubenstein Library.
  - Nightingale, Florence, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 3)
    The Soldier's Friend, 1856, full portrait engraving. Includes slide.
  - Nixon, Pat Ireland (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Noeggerath, Emil, 1827-1895 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Nonne, Max (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Noorden, Karl Harko von (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Nosler, D. George (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Nothnagel, Hermann (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Novak, Emil (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Occo, Adolphus (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Ochsner, Albert John (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Oddi, Oddo degli, 1478-1558 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Oertel, Max Josef (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Oliver, Keith (Duke '44) (Box 7, Folder 48)
    Signed snapshot photograph of Oliver with colleague Frederick Michael Hanson.
  - Olmsted, J. M. D. (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Olshausen, Robert (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - O'Malley, Charles D. (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Opie, Eugene L. (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Oppenheim, Hermann, 2 items; box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Includes a printed sheet with biography in German.
  - Orfila, Matthieu-Joseph-Bonaventure (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Original Faculty of Medicine, Johns Hopkins (Box 7, Folder 54)
    Print illustration of 18 faculty, including Billings, Fleschel, Halsted, Kelly, Mackenzie, Osler, Thayer, and Welch.
  - Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Large black-and-white reproduction photograph of Osler in his office.